Data and Machine Learning Engineer

Data | Machine Learning Engineer

Bangalore, Karnataka

Data Engineer turned ML Engineer with 2+ years of experience, I possess the wealth of both fields which allows me to gain in-depth knowledge from processing data to building models to gaining insights. I'm Seeking for a challenging position as a ML Engineer where my analytical skills will be further developed, utilized, and gain sufficient knowledge for career advancement in the organization. Highly skilled in python programming, machine learning, data visualization, and creative thinking

Work Experience

Data and Machine Learning Engineer

6th Grai

6th Graii

Bengaluru, Karnataka

June 2017 to Present

- Fulfilled all data science duties as per client requirement from machine learning models to data visualizations.
- Assisted in developing a yield prediction model using weather, soil, remote sensing and farmer-provided data and increasing the accuracy
- Predictive modelling for Spray windows using weather, growth stages of crop and farmer-provided data.
- · Taking care of the complete ETL process on raw weather data from multiple sources and performing various analysis over them.
- Developed Dashboard apps for Growth stage analysis of crops and weed detection using NDVI.
- Designing, creating, testing, maintaining and managing the complete data management & processing systems on AWS.
- Developed internal tools for routine tasks.

Data scientist Intern

ORMAE

OTTIVIAL

Bengaluru, Karnataka

March 2017 to May 2017

- Contributed to the data analysis, feature selection and applying different machine learning models on the project Anomaly Detection in Web Infrastructure System of a Major Retail Industry.
- Assisted in the implementation and testing of the heuristic algorithm in Applied Operation Research project.
- Predicting website traffic during peak hours and holiday sales estimation.

Education

M.Tech in Software Engineering

M S Ramaiah Institute of Technology

Bengaluru, Karnataka

August 2014 to October 2016

B.E in Computer Science and Engineering

Brindavan College of Engineering

Bengaluru, Karnataka

July 2010 to June 2014

Skills

Apache Hadoop Ecosystem and Spark (1 year), Data Analysis (3 years), R Programming (2 years), Python (3 years), Scala (1 year), Machine Learning (2 years), Django & Dashboard development (2 years)

Publications

Performance Evaluation of Social Network Analysis Algorithms Using Distributed and In-Memory Computing Environments"

http://www.journal4research.org/articles/J4RV2I3026.pdf

2016-05

Analysis of social interactions among various data sets in a distributed and in-memory environment (Apache Spark) and also the performance evaluation of Spark cluster over a variety of social network data of different sizes.

Additional Information

Proiects:

- M.Tech Final year project: Improved Methods to Analyze Interactions among Participants in Social Networks using Distributed Computing Paradigms. Analysis of social interactions among various data sets in a distributed an In-memory environment (Cluster of 5 Nodes running Apache Spark- Hadoop) and also the performance evaluation of cluster over a variety of social network data of different sizes.
- B.E Final year project: Statistical weather data analysis over Bangalore region using Remote Sensing to obtain useful information and provide meaningful forecast, verification and measures.

Languages: Python,R Programming, SQL and Scala.

Operating System/Cloud Platform: AWS, Google Cloud Platform, Windows and Linux.

Tools: Apache Hadoop Ecosystem and Spark.

Dashboard development: Django, Dash Plotly

Machine Learning Libraries: Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Keras, Pytorch

Skill Set

Data & Modeling: Data Analysis/Wrangling, Web Scraping, Statistical Inference, Regression Modeling, Machine Learning, Deep Learning (CNN, RNN), Computer Vision, NLP (Natural Language Processing).

Professional Competencies

- ❖ Systematic in your analysis approach.
- ❖ Skilled in the practices of data analysis.
- . Commitment to Carrier.
- ❖ Aiming at excellence in work through self motivation.